Guide to the Harold D. Gunn Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Provincial Files, 1908-1951, Series I
  - Plateau Province
    - General
      - The Sura-Angas-Ankwe group pagan people of the Plateau area, Nigeria, undated (Box 16, Folder 394)
    - Jemaa division
      - Tribal and administrative organization of the Jemaa division [by A. B. Mathews], 1934 (Box 17, Folder 395)
      - Ninzam district, administration of [by A. B. Mathews], 1934 (Box 17, Folder 396)
    - Jos division
      - Amo, Buji and Jere districts, Plateau Province notes and abstracts, and selections make by H. D. Gunn, undated (Box 17, Folder 397)
      - The Bi Rom (also written "Birom") [by J. G. Davies], undated (Box 17, Folder 398)
      - Jos divisional organization, proposals for excision of Jos and Bukuru native towns, 1931[?]-1943[?] (Box 17, Folder 399)
      - Miango- Pitti Affray, 1930 February 9 (Box 17, Folder 400)
      - Reorganization report on the Amo, Buji and Jere districts of Jose division [by E. H. M. Counsell with Resident's covering report by E. S. Pembleton], 1936 (Box 17, Folder 401)
      - Reorganization report on the Rukuba tribe [by E. H. H. Counsel with resident's cover report by E. S. Pembleton], 1935 (Box 17, Folder 402)
      - Joint report by J. A. Hilton and G. Lorimer on the Plateau boundary, as affected by the Rukuba reorganization, undated (Box 17, Folder 403)
    - Pankshen and Shendam divisions
      - Confidential memo on ethnic conflict in Shendam, 1933 January 12 (Box 17, Folder 404)
      - Garkawa tribe, anthropological notes on, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 405)
      - Hausa and Abakwariga in Shendam division, revision of tax assessment of, 1939 February 2 (Box 17, Folder 406)
      - Jangali Collection, Hardodi, 1937 November 11 (Box 17, Folder 407)
      - Jepal district, Jepal Federation, 1939 February 27 (Box 17, Folder 408)
      - Kaleri district, progress report, 1935 December (Box 17, Folder 409)
      - Mentol tribe
        - Historical and ethnological notes on Mentol tribe, 1931 August 11 (Box 17, Folder 410)
        - Reorganization report [by E. S. Pembleton], 1938 (Box 17, Folder 411)
      - Pai district, miscellaneous correspondence on disturbances in, 1935 July 29 (Box 17, Folder 412)
        - Reorganization report on the Kofyer-Namu-Dimmuk area [by C. W. Rowling with Resident's covering report by F. M. Noad], undated (Box 17, Folder 413)
        - Reorganization report on Jepal-Kofyer area [by E. S. Pembleton], 1934 (Box 17, Folder 414)
      - Ron district, report on [by A. B. Mathews], 1934 (Box 17, Folder 415)
      - Sha-Monguna unit, progress report, 1936 January (Box 17, Folder 416)
      - Wase district, proposal for revisional assessment, 1933-1934 (Box 17, Folder 417)
    - Other districts
      - Borsari district, assessment on [by C. W. Rowling], 1928 (Box 17, Folder 418)
      - Dass district, skeleton assessment report [compiled from Barnicot's and other reports], 1932-1933 (Box 17, Folder 419)
      - Ganawari district, Beikip of Tsafi [by G. C. Monckton], 1929 August 6 (Box 17, Folder 420)
      - Wamba district, village head of Nakere, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 421)
  - Sokoto Province
    - General
      - Abstracts and extracts, 1951 March 29 (Box 18, Folder 422)
      - Burmawa, notes on the Burmawa of Sokoto [by F. de F. Daniel], 1926 September 20 (Box 18, Folder 423)
      - Confidential memo on population movement and immigration, 1926-1938 (Box 18, Folder 424)
    - Argunu division (also called "Emirate")
      - Balawa district, assessment report- Balawa district of Argunu division, undated (Box 18, Folder 425)
      - Classification of Fulani, replies to questionnaire, undated (Box 18, Folder 426)
      - Notes and extracts, 1951 March 30 (Box 18, Folder 427)
      - Emire of Argunu's council, reorganization of, 1934 November 17 (Box 18, Folder 428)
      - Some notes on the agricultural and pastoral implements of the peoples of Argunu Emirate, undated (Box 18, Folder 429)
    - Ilo independent district, report on, 1937 February 6 (Box 18, Folder 430)
    - Other districts
      - Bin Yam district, handwritten notes on, undated (Box 18, Folder 431)
      - Bunza district, assessment report [by D. J. Muffett], 1948 (Box 18, Folder 432)
      - Dabai district
        - Achifawa [of Dabai], historical and anthropological report [by A. B. Mathews], undated (Box 18, Folder 433)
        - Assessment report of [by N. C. McClintock], 1948 June 29 (Box 18, Folder 434)
        - Gobirawa, administration of, undated (Box 18, Folder 435)
        - Gwadabawa, comments on rural conditions in, 1949 December 23 (Box 18, Folder 436)
      - Kaigo district, Fulani grazing areas in, 1949 December 24 (Box 18, Folder 437)
      - Yaurawa (also called Gungawa) district
        - Anthropological and historical report on [by A. B. Mathews], undated (Box 18, Folder 438)
        - Historical notes on Yauri, 1929 October 21 (Box 18, Folder 439)
  - Zaria province
    - General
      - Agricultural economy in Zaria: disintegration of villages and dispersal of farmers, 1945 December 11 (Box 19, Folder 440)
      - Districts of Zaria Emirate, 1943 November (Box 19, Folder 441)
      - Extracts and notes, 1951 May 10 (Box 19, Folder 442)
      - The Habe dynasties, undated (Box 19, Folder 443)
      - Historical and ethnological notes on Zaria, undated (Box 19, Folder 444)
      - Kadara
        - Kadara tribe, undated (Box 19, Folder 445)
        - Notes, extracts and census reports, undated (Box 19, Folder 446)
      - Kagoro tribe, social organization and economy of, undated (Box 19, Folder 447)
      - The Kai-na-fara, undated (Box 19, Folder 448)
      - Katab
        - Assessment report on the Kataba tribe Zangon Katab district, undated (Box 19, Folder 449)
        - Katab district, reassessment, 1922 September-October (Box 19, Folder 450)
        - Questionnaire, undated (Box 19, Folder 451)
      - Kisra legends [memo from the Secretary of the Northern Provinces], 1931 July 17 (Box 19, Folder 452)
      - Notes on villages areas and hamlets, undated (Box 19, Folder 453)
      - Pagan peoples of the middle Niger and Zaria, undated (Box 19, Folder 454)
      - Preliminary notes on Zaria Emirate and Soba village dry, undated (Box 19, Folder 455)
      - Report on tanning industry, 1947 March 7 (Box 19, Folder 456)
      - Zaria Province annual report, 1927 April 8 (Box 19, Folder 457)
      - Zaria Province field notes, 1949-1951 (Box 19, Folder 458)
      - Zaria Province field notes, 1949-1951 (Box 19, Folder 459)
      - Zaria -Plateau province, tribal adjustments between, 1934 November 9 (Box 19, Folder 460)
    - Districts
      - Anchau district
        - Assessment report on, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 461)
        - Correspondence on Anchau Maguazawa and Kargi report [by W. R. Shirley], 1932 (Box 19, Folder 462)
      - Chawai district
        - An administrative report on [by J. C. Drummond-Hay], 1930 (Box 19, Folder 463)
        - Assessment report, 1930 August (Box 19, Folder 464)
      - Ikara district, assessment report on [by W. T. Barnicot], 1933 (Box 19, Folder 465)
      - Kachia district, assessment report on the Jaba tribe of, 1933 August (Box 19, Folder 466)
      - Kajuru district
        - Kajuru, assessment report on a representative village area, 1934 February 9 (Box 19, Folder 467)
        - Kajuru reassessment report, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 468)
      - Kauru district, notes on the Kauru district (Moslem part), undated (Box 19, Folder 469)
- Ethnic Groups, 1921-1967, Series II
  The files in this series document the perspectives of colonial officials and experts on the nomadic cattle herding Fulani and three other larger groups (Hausa, Tuareg and Wolof). Arranged alphabetically by ethnic group, most of the files are on the Fulani, perhaps because of their significance in terms of the size of the area they occupied and patterns of their seasonal migration. The series also includes an equally large number of files on the Tiv people which is categorized under Benue province where the Tiv lived in their own administrative unit called "Tiv division."
  Researchers would also find in this series questionnaires specially designed by anthropologists to collect ethnographic data on social organization and economic activities of the Fulani and Tuareg.
  - Fulani (also written as "Fulbe")
    - Anthropological notes on Fulani tribe, 1927 December 9 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Bororo Fulani
      - Information regarding, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Memorandum from Secretary of Northern provinces to Resident of Plateau province, 1926 July 7 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Memorandum from Sergent F. G. Reynolds, the Assistant District Officer of Potiskum division to Resident of Bornu Province, 1926 October 16 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Bibliographie Foulbe, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Bush Pagan Fulani [from manuscript notes in possession of C. K. Meek], undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Cattle Fulani, organization of, 1936 November 29 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Fulani of Gwandu division, report on, 1934 July 31 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Fulani in the Emirate of Bornu, sketch of their immigration, principal tribes and chiefs, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Fulani tribe- anthropological notes, 1927 December 9 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Historical notes on Kazaure [a Fulani Emirate], undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Kitije Fulani, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Katsina Fulbe
      - Answer to Questionnaire #20 [memo by the Resident of Jos division], 1927 April 1 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Reply to Professor Seligman's questionnaire, 1927 October 1 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Nomad Fulani
      - [Extract on nomad Fulani from] Gumel Emirate gazetteer, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - "Nomad" Fulani in Fika, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - Questionnaire, nomad Fulani (Bororo and Kitiyen), 1921 October 17 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - The tale of Adhr first of the Fulani, undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Hausa
    - Hausa quarters of Yoruba towns [by G. J. Afolabi Ojo], undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Sociological and economic aspects of African trade and crafts, a contribution on the social-economic structure of the Hausa enclaves in Ghana [by Irmgard Sellnow], undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Situational ethnicity in Africa with special reference to the Hausa [by John N. Paden], 1967 November 2 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Tuareg, questionnaire concerning, 1927 August 26 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Wolof, the Gullah, Gambia, undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
- Topical Files, 1913-1950, Series III
  The files in this series are arranged alphabetically within the five sections relating to the following: Beliefs, cults and native religion; Land tenure and land use practices; Marriage customs; Native court cases, and Political notes and policy papers. Producers of these files include anthropologists and officers, such as J. O. Clarke, K. Dewar, D. A. Percival, J. G. Davies and C. K Meek.
  Files on religion cover wide-ranging issues surrounding witchcraft, fertility rituals, and cults of various types. Likewise, files under land tenure and land use practices provide useful demographic and economic information, including population size by district, and household-level data on budgets and livelihoods. Files on marriage concern customary practices, such as concubinage, dowry, and wife exchange ("marriage by exchange"), that seemed "backward" in the eyes of colonial officials. The series also contains files on the functioning of native courts and policy papers that discuss the future of Nigeria.
  - Beliefs, cults and native religion
    - Bolawa religion, general notes on [by Smyth], 1923 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Circumcision among the Sheni, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Epa, Are and Eji: three Yoruba fertility (prosperity) ceremonies [by J. O. Clarke], undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Garyo cult (anti-witchcraft) in Tiv division, 1948-1949 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Hoyo (castigation of witches)
      - Hoyo in Benue province, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Hoyo in Masev/Ngeve [from K. Dewar, district officer of Abinsi division], 1933 October 20 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Magiro cult (of Dakarkari tribe), anthropological notes on, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Maguzawa beliefs [by T. H. Sandford], 1949 January (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Makka (Tasa) cult, Mambila area [extracts from reports by D. A. Percival and Rev. Paul Gebauer], 1938 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Notes from religion, myth and magic in Tangale-Waja district [by John S. Hall], undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Notes on witchcraft in its relation to administrative problems [by K. Dewar], undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Nyambuan ("Juju") movement [by the divisional officer of Tiv], 1939 September 8 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Report on the sacrifices at feast of new yams as performed among the Edda tribe and other customs in Vogue at Owutu Edda (Afikpo division, Ogoja province), 1928 January 28 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Spear cult, 1929 August 12 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Tor-msor ("Beer Chief") activities in Tiv, 1945-1948 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Land tenure and land use practices
    - Birom land tenure
      - Birom land tenure and grazing rights, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - A note on [by J. G. Davies], undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Blue book returns, churches, chapels and population in Gombe Emirate, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Farm and family budgets for three households in Riyom village, 1945 May 21 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Intensive census, Tarke Hamlet (handwritten notes and statistical data), 1949 May 19 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Land tenure in Afon district, Ilorin province [by Captain Burnett], 1913 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Land tenure in Yoruba provinces [by H. L. Ward Price], 1933 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Land tenure and usage, circular from the Secretary of northern provinces, 1947 September 20 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Northern provinces statistical returns and population, etc., 1937 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Population statistics, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Report on a farm survey of the area occupied by the Gyel community of the Bi Rom tribe in the Jos division [by J. G. Davies], 1944 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Marriage customs
    - Anthropological notes on the marriage customs of Yeskwas tribe [excerpts from report by Wilson Haffenden], undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Concubinage and dowry, undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Kanuri marriage customs, notes on, undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Marriage by exchange in Nigeria, a disappearing institution [by C. K. Meek], undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Matrimonial cases [memo from the assistant district officer of Pategi-Lafiagi division to Resident of Ilorin province], 1939 April 13 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Registration of native marriages in native courts, Gombe, Bauchi, undated (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Native court cases
    - Alkali's court, Briniwa and Guri districts, Shendam division, undated (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Bashar native court "D" grade, Wase district, Shendam division, 1940 September 9 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Duara and Kazaure native courts [memo], 1924 June 23 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Ron native court, Panskshin division, 1939 December 5 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - West Tangale court, general matters (native courts), undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Political notes and policy papers on the future of Nigeria
    - Confidential notes on native administration and political development in British tropical Africa [report by Lord Hailey], 1940-1942 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Political and constitutional papers on the future of Nigeria, 1945-1946 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Report on local government in the northern provinces of Nigeria [by K. P. Maddocks], 1950 December 14 (Box 21, Folder 40)
- Northern Nigerian Languages, 1921-1968, Series IV
  This series includes a large collection of vocabularies and anthropological notes on more than forty alphabetically arranged local ("native") languages in northern Nigeria. These vocabularies seem to have been collected over a long period of time by several individuals, including missionaries and district officers. The series also features a comparative table and other linguistic tools designed by researchers to determine similarities and differences among these languages. There is also one file containing correspondence notes exchanged between Harold D. Gunn and Joseph H. Greenberg concerning the languages of Northern Nigeria.
  - General linguistic notes, research materials and correspondence
    - Comparative table [percentage of words common to two languages], undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence notes [on Northern Nigerian languages] with Joseph H. Greenberg, 1955-1961 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Morgan's vocabulary [handwritten notes], 1921 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Notes on, and vocabularies of, northern Nigerian languages: Tangale, Wurkum, Peri, Gwandum, Awak, Chonge, Kamu, Tula, Waja, Dadiya, etc.), undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Plateau languages; Bashar, Ambo, Rukuba, Buti, Mado, Mabo, Horom, Koro, Funtu, Kadara, etc. [by Kay Williamson and others], undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Provisional checklist of Nigerian languages [prepared by the Institute of Linguistics], undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Recording text No. 2: Northern Nigeria (notes and questionnaires), undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Vocabularies and correspondence notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Vocabularies of native languages
    - Afu glossary, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Agatu vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Akpa vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Amo vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Ankwe district vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Ayu vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Bashar vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Baya vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Boju vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Borgu division
      - Languages of the Borgu division, undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - Notes on the languages of Borgu and the ethnography of the Borgu people, undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Borrom (?), not labeled vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Bura, Nyimaltu, Jara and Hina languages, vocabularies of, undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Burum vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Buti ("Butawa") vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Chadic vocabularies, 1968 June 7 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Dong language, vocabulary of [explanatory notes by Desmond MacBridge], 1930 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Gerkawa vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Gwandara (Gurku) vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Igumale vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Kaidi Kanembu, the language of the [by Johannes Lukas], undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Kamatanan vocabulary [by C. K. Meek], 1930 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Koro tribe, anthropological notes and vocabularies, 1921 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Kulu vocabulary [compiled by Reverend C. W. Gainter], undated (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Kunuri vocabulary [by J. R. Patterson], undated (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Mada, Arago and Gwandarawa vocabularies, undated (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Mada sentences, 1926 May (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Mandingue- Alphabet [also enclosed a letter from H. Stover Kulp to H. Gunn], 1956 November 29 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Montol vocabulary and anthropological notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Mumuye titles and terms, a brief glossary of [compiled by Mr. Brinklow, Sudan United Mission], 1948 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Ngizim (southern) vocabularies, undated (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Ninzim district vocabulary, 1921 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Nyan-nyan vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Pankshin division vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Pia (Piya) vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Potopo vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Rukuba vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Sheni vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Waja vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Yergam (Taro) vocabulary, undated (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Yola vocabularies, undated (Box 22, Folder 49)
- Harold D. Gunn Personal Papers, 1931-1982, Series V
  A considerable number of the files in this series consists of Harold Gunn's letters personally written to, and received from, different individuals. The series also contains research materials and field notes on the provinces and divisions he visited at different times while working for the International African Institute. There are also some fragment notes, extracts and newspaper clips which were enclosed in the correspondence. The series also includes two grant applications, documenting Harold Gunn's attempts to obtain funds for arranging and preserving this collection. Also included are some lecture notes for a sociology class and a feature article on "Black Music" that appeared in a school bulletin.
  - Fragment notes and index cards
    - Catalog cards and fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Extracts and drafts, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Fragments and notes, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Index cards and fragment notes, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Grant applications
    - Grant application to American Philosophical Society for categorizing documents, 1980 December 28 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Grant application to National Endowment for Humanities to archive and index collection of British Colonial Nigerian documents, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Letters and correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Miss Pym, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with J. M. D. Crossey and other curators, 1976-1981 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Letter of the British Organizing Committee of the International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1933 November 15 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Letters from J. M. O. Abraham to conservation officials in Ilorin, 1938 October 30 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Letter to Frank [research assistant], undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Maps, bibliography, etc., undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Personal correspondence, [1948?]-1957, 1981-1982 (Box 23, Folder 14 - 20)
    - Shendam and Pankshin divisions correspondence, notes, files, 1950-1951, undated (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Reports by Captain Abraham, 1931 September 26 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - "The Sura-Angas-Ankwe Group," correspondence, research materials (see also Volume V of Pagan Peoples of the Plateau Area), 1950-1981, undated (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Notes on provinces and divisions
    - Benue province, Gajette, lists of files, etc., undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Benue province (II), notes (A), Idoma, undated (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Benue province (II), notes (B1), Wukari, Tiv and Lafia, undated (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Benue province (II), notes (B2), Wukari, Tiv, Lafia and Nasarawa, undated (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Benue province (II), notes (B3), Lafia, Nasarawa, Tiv and Idoma, undated (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Benue province (III) [divisional notes], 1950 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Divisional notes on Bornu and Kano provinces, undated (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Ethnographic survey notes, Zaria province (Pagaus, east sector), Vols. I & II, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Extracts from pictographic dictionary; some road signs, undated (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Ilorin and Niger provinces (including divisions), undated (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Kabba province, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Kabba, notes on Kabba division, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - List of administrative files and anthropological & historical notes, undated (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Notes and files on Bauchi province (Vol. I), 1950 (Box 25, Folder 37)